healthinsurance.org 2005-12-11

# Privacy Policy for the Health Insurance Resource Center

This Privacy Policy discloses the information privacy practices for the Web site you are currently visiting. You may be accessing this site through a secure server at linus.pounce.com -- this is a server registered to our Web site management company, pounce.com. You may contact healthinsurance.org or our management company via e-mail through this form or via postal mail at healthinsurance.org. c/o pounce.com, 19350 Ireland Court, Lakeville, MN 55044.

Throughout the policy, we refer to information that can identify you as a specific individual, such as your name, phone number, e-mail address as "personal information." Further, personal information includes any information involving your health or medical history.

**Disclosure of your personal information**

We do not disclose, sell, trade or give away your personal information to anyone, except as needed to provide you with a health insurance quote in the specific instances shown here:

  * **H** **ealth insurance company.** We provide personal information directly to one or more health insurance carriers that offer quotes to persons living in your state. They are allowed to use this information solely to provide you with the health insurance quote you are requesting; and they are contractually obligated to maintain strict confidentiality.

  * **Non-profit associations.** In those ZIP areas where have an agreement with a non-profit association in your state which provides access to health insurance as one of its benefits (an example of this type of association is [Communicating for Agriculture & The Self-Employed](http://www.selfemployedcountry.org/)), we will forward your contact information to them for the purpose of having their licensed enrollers provide you with a quote on your health insurance. They are allowed to use this information solely to provide you with the health insurance quote you are requesting, and they are contractually obligated to maintain strict confidentiality.

Outside of these two exceptions, we will not share your personal information with third parties.

**Use of your contact information**

The use of your contact information is restricted to the following:

  * **In regards to your quote.** The insurance company or non-profit association in part one may use your personal information to get in touch with you when necessary to provide you with a quote or to process your application should you choose to be insured by them . For example, the company or association may e-mail, call or mail you to provide you with a quote or to seek additional information that is needed to provide you with a quote.

  * **Visitor satisfaction or other products.** As of the last update of this privacy policy on April 26, 2005, healthinsurance.org _**has never sent an e-mail to a visitor other than in direct response to a question submitted though our contact form,**_ and at this time has no plans to do so.

However, as of July 15, 2002 we added a question at the end of our quote-request form allowing visitors to opt-out of any future mailings, _should they occur._

In the unlikely event we were to contact you, if would be to survey your satisfaction of our service and/or to inform you of additional products and services. In addition, if any such e-mails are sent the sender would clearly be identified as "healthinsurance.org" and you would be directed to a Web page on the healthinsurance.org site to access any information or offers described. Also see information below on "opting out."

**Anonymous information.**

This is information about visitors to our site that does not personally identify you, such as the number of visitors to our Web site. You may be included in that number, but are never personally identified. We may share information such as the number of visitors to our Web site from a particular state with partners, but never their names and contact information (except to provide you a quote as disclosed above).

**No cookies**

Some sites use "cookies" -- small pieces of information stored by your web browser to help a particular system recognize you and the pages you visited in a website. Some sites use them for your convenience, so you may retrieve information on a later visit to that Web site. This site does not use cookies and your personal information is not stored for later retrieval. Your information is not accessible to others through a Web browser of other means.

**Changes to this policy**

We will provide notice of changes in our information privacy practices on this Privacy Policy page, with a notation of when the change became effective; and those changed policies will affect only the information collected _after_ the change.

You may opt out of receiving satisfaction surveys and/or information on additional products and services from us.

If we are going to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your personal information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes to our information privacy practices that do not affect the personal information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice in the privacy portion of our website notifying users of the change.

**Opting out or deleting your information from our database**

If you want to opt out of any surveys, notices or offers you may contact us by e-mail through this form or by mail at healthinsurance.org, c/o pounce.com, 19350 Ireland Court, Lakeville, MN 55044. We are available to answer any questions you may have about our privacy policy or our information privacy practices; if you have any questions, please e-mail us at through this form. Please also e-mail us if you have any comments or suggestions for improvements to this privacy policy or our Web site(s).

Information gathered for health insurance requests is stored for a limited time on our Web server. You may request to have your information deleted from our records by e-mailing us through this form and we will do so within one business day.

This privacy policy applies to this healthinsurance.org-controlled Web site, and may not apply to other Web sites that are owned and/or operated by our Web site management company, pounce.com, nor other sites linked to or from us (see "Links to Other Web sites" below).

**Links to Other Web sites**

Our Web site contains links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links you are "clicking" to another Web site. healthinsurance.org is not responsible for the information privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. This includes instances when we do not currently have a carrier in your state -- or any other instance -- where we redirect you to a [co-branded site managed by eHealthInsurance.com](https://www.ehealthinsurance.com/ehi/Alliance?allid=pou14050). We encourage you to read the privacy policies of these linked Web sites as their information privacy practices may differ from ours.
